<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Chicago History &#8211; Chicago Public Library</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/category/chicago-history/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.chipublib.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 16:50:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Celebrating Chicago African American Painter Charles White</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/celebrating-african-american-painter-charles-white/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 21:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cynthia]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African American history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=178154</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On April 2nd we celebrate the 100th anniversary of the birth of African American painter and graphic designer Charles White. According to Roosevelt University professor Erik Gellman, White not only “applied his art as a weapon in Chicago,” but he discovered a unique appreciation and love for African-American history not at school, but at Chicago…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On April 2<sup>nd</sup> we celebrate the 100<sup>th</sup> anniversary of the birth of <a href="http://iraaa.museum.hamptonu.edu/page/Charles-White-and-the-Black-Chicago-Renaissance" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">African American painter and graphic designer Charles White</a>. <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1486601126" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">According to Roosevelt University professor Erik Gellman</a>, White not only “applied his art as a weapon in Chicago,” but he discovered a unique appreciation and love for African-American history not at school, but at Chicago Public Library.</p>

<p>White took an early interest in art. His mother bought him an art kit when he was around seven years old. While attending Englewood High School he helped design sets for school plays. When he was fourteen, the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/about-hall-branch/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">George Cleveland Hall Branch</a> opened and White found himself spending a good number of hours poring over the book collection curated by head librarian, <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/vivian-g-harsh-librarian-of-the-chicago-black-renaissance/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Vivian G. Harsh</a>. He was most impressed by Alain Locke’s <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?custom_edit=false&amp;query=%28title%3A%28new+negro%29+AND+contributor%3A%28locke%29+%29&amp;searchType=bl&amp;suppress=true" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">The New Negro.</a></p>
<p>During the Depression, artist George Neal assembled some of his students into an Arts Crafts Guild that collaborated on work, held parties to help members attend the School of the Art Institute of Chicago and exhibited everywhere from the Wabash Y to vacant lots. White took a few of his drawings to a Guild meeting and became a member. Other members included <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=margaret+burroughs&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Margaret Burroughs</a> and Eldzier Cortor.</p>
<p>In 1937, White won a scholarship to the School of the Art Institute, despite not graduating from high school. Like plenty of other “starving artists,” White took a position with the <a href="https://www.loc.gov/rr/program/bib/newdeal/fap.html" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">WPA’s Federal Art Project</a> where he worked to produce one public art painting every five weeks. It was during his tenure that the WPA asked White to create a mural for the Hall Branch. <a href="https://www.aaa.si.edu/collections/interviews/oral-history-interview-charles-w-white-11484#transcript" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">According to a 1965 interview</a>, White insists that the subject for his oil on canvas mural was “5 outstanding Negroes.” Four of the subjects chosen were <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=george+washington+carver&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">George Washington Carver</a>, <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=booker+t.+washington&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Booker T. Washington</a>, <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=sojourner+truth&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Sojourner Truth</a> and <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=marian+anderson&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Marian Anderson</a>. Images of, or even newspaper reports of, the mural’s unveiling or display have yet to be uncovered. It seems people remember the mural, but sadly there are no long-lasting mementos.</p>

<p>By the time of the <a href="https://archive.org/details/americannegroexp00amer" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">1940 American Negro Exposition</a>, White’s <em>There Were No Crops This Year</em> won a first prize award and graced the cover of the catalog for the exposition’s Henry O. Tanner Gallery. At the same time, the Associated Negro Press commissioned his <em>History of the Negro Press</em> mural for their exhibit at the Exposition. White eventually left Chicago in 1941 and taught at Dillard University where he met sculptor <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?f_TOPIC_HEADINGS=Catlett%2C+Elizabeth%2C&amp;locked=false&amp;pagination_page=1&amp;query=elizabeth+catlett&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=keyword&amp;sort=relevancy" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Elizabeth Catlett</a>. The two were briefly married. In 1965, White left New Orleans for Los Angeles where he stayed until his death in 1979.</p>
<p>This summer <a href="http://www.artic.edu/about/press/press-release/charles-white-retrospective" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">the Art Institute is hosting a Charles White retrospective</a>. We hope to see you there! If you'd like more information about Charles White, please enjoy the <a href="https://cpl.thehistorymakers.org/stories/2;q=%22charles%20white%22;pg=1;pgS=30" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">interviews with his contemporaries at The HistoryMakers</a> or  check out these resources:</p>
<p><a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/948124126">Charles White</a></p>
<p><a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1917553126">Charles White</a></p>
<p><a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/552642126">Reaches of the Heart</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mural Honors 20 Iconic Chicago Women</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/mural-honors-20-iconic-chicago-women/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's history]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=176996</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you walked by the Chicago Cultural Center and noticed a colorful mural by artist and MacArthur Fellow Kerry James Marshall? The large 132 foot by 100 foot mural can be viewed on the Garland Court facade, between Washington and Randolph streets. Marshall describes the vision behind his mural, "My idea was to make of…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you walked by the Chicago Cultural Center and noticed a colorful mural by artist and MacArthur Fellow <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=Kerry+James+Marshall&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Kerry James Marshall?</a> The large 132 foot by 100 foot mural can be viewed on the Garland Court facade, between Washington and Randolph streets.</p>
<p>Marshall describes the vision behind his mural, "My idea was to make of the trees a kind of Forest Rushmore acknowledging the contribution of 20 women who've worked to shape the cultural landscape of the city, past and present."</p>
<p>For <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/news/celebrate-womens-history-month-with-cpl-4/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Women's History Month</a> let's take a closer look at five of the women highlighted in Kerry James Marshall's mural.
</p>
<h2 class="o-heading--large o-heading--large@mobile o-heading--large-wysiwyg">Abena Joan Brown (1928-2015)</h2>
<p>Brown was a social worker, businesswoman and theater producer who started Chicago's <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-eta-creative-arts-foundation/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">eta Creative Arts Foundation.</a> The non profit organization was founded in 1971 to provide training and performance opportunities to youth and adults. It showcases works written and performed by black artists. Brown was named the "mother of Chicago's black arts community" by the Chicago Sun-Times. Brown has received many local awards and accolades, including having a section of South Chicago Avenue (between 75th and 76th Streets) renamed in her honor in 2011.</p>
<h2 class="o-heading--large o-heading--large@mobile o-heading--large-wysiwyg">Sandra Cisneros</h2>
<p>Author <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Cisneros%2C+Sandra&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Sandra Cisneros</a> was born in Chicago and grew up in a family where "library cards were mandatory." In 2009, her first novel <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=house+on+mango+street&amp;searchType=title" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">The House on Mango Street</a> was celebrated as CPL's <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/the-house-on-mango-street-one-book-one-chicago-spring-2009/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">One Book, One Chicago</a> selection. The coming-of-age novel set in Humboldt Park served as the inspiration for <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/browse/teens/youmedia/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">YOUmedia's</a> pilot project encouraging teens to explore and create digital projects based on the novel's themes. Cisneros' books have been translated into over a dozen languages and are required reading in classrooms across the nation. Her numerous awards include Chicago's Fifth Star Award and the National Medal of Arts. </p>
<h2 class="o-heading--large o-heading--large@mobile o-heading--large-wysiwyg">Harriet Monroe (1860-1936) </h2>
<p>Poet <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=%22Monroe%2C+Harriet%22&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Harriet Monroe</a> was born and raised in Chicago. She was launched onto an international stage with her <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/421576126" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Columbian Ode,</a> commissioned as part of the festivities for the 1893 World’s Fair. However, she is best known for founding and serving as the long-time editor of <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/563308126?active_tab=bib_info" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Poetry</a> magazine until her death in 1936. Monroe established an “Open Door” policy for the magazine, “May the great poet we are looking for never find it shut, or half-shut against his ample genius,” still used today, over one hundred years later. In those years, Monroe published early works of what’s become a who’s who of poetry list including <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Pound%2C+Ezra&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Ezra Pound,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Eliot%2C+T.+S.&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">T.S. Eliot,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Frost%2C+Robert&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Robert Frost,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Hughes%2C+Langston&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Langston Hughes,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Millay%2C+Edna+St.+Vincent&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Edna St. Vincent Millay,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Brooks%2C+Gwendolyn&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Gwendolyn Brooks</a> (also featured on Marshall’s mural), <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Yeats%2C+W.+B.&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">William Butler Yeats,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Plath%2C+Sylvia&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Sylvia Plath,</a> <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Cummings%2C+E.+E.&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">E.E. Cummings</a> and many others including <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Sandburg%2C+Carl&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Carl Sandburg</a> and his poem “Chicago” which first described Chicago as the “City of the Big Shoulders.”  </p>
<h2 class="o-heading--large o-heading--large@mobile o-heading--large-wysiwyg">Jackie Taylor</h2>
<p><a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1891886126" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Taylor,</a> born in Chicago's Cabrini Green, is a distinguished director, producer actress, educator, singer, playwright and founder of <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_post/black-ensemble-theater-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Black Ensemble Theater.</a> She found the Black Ensemble Theater in 1976 with the mission of ending racism in local theater. The theater has a national reputation for outstanding original productions and exceptional education outreach programs. Seven and a half years ago, Taylor broke ground on the new 20-million-dollar Black Ensemble Theater Cultural Center (4450 N. Clark Street) which opened on November 18, 2011. She has written and produced more than 100 plays and musical biographies in addition to acting in several major films.</p>
<h2 class="o-heading--large o-heading--large@mobile o-heading--large-wysiwyg">Margaret Taylor-Burroughs (1917-2011)</h2>
<p><a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=Margaret+Burroughs&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Dr. Margaret Taylor Goss Burroughs</a> was an artist, poet, educator and co-founder of the <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=DuSable+Museum+of+African-American+History&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">DuSable Museum of African-American History.</a> In 1939, Burroughs helped found the <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=south+side+community+art+center&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=subject" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Southside Community Arts Center.</a> The center served as a gallery and study for black artists and students. in 1961, Burroughs and her husband, Charles, found the Ebony Museum of Negro History and Art in the home at 3806 S. Michigan Avenue. The museum was later renamed the DuSable Museum of African American History and moved to its current location in the Washington Park neighborhood. She worked as an elementary teacher and then a high school teacher. Besides her career as an educator and an institution builder, Burroughs was an artist and prominent author of children's books and poetry.</p>
<p>Continue to celebrate Women's History Month by attending a <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/events/search/fq=program:(52ec52e0cb8b1e0000000016)" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">library program</a> at a branch near you, or by viewing an <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/news/womens-history-month-art-exhibits-at-budlong-woods-hwlc-woodson/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">exhibit</a> on women's history.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago’s Women of Gospel Music</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/chicagos-women-of-gospel-music/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 22:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Book One Chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OBOC 2017-2018]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=175842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chicago was influential in the beginning of gospel music, and women were part of gospel from the beginning. CPL has numerous resources to help you discover more about some of these magnificent Chicago women, past and present. Often the first name to come to mind for Chicagoans is Mahalia Jackson. Let's meet a few of…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chicago was influential in the beginning of gospel music, and <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?locked=false&amp;query=women+gospel+music&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=smart" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">women were part of gospel from the beginning</a>. CPL has numerous resources to help you discover more about some of these magnificent Chicago women, past and present.</p>
<p>Often the first name to come to mind for Chicagoans is <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?f_AUDIENCE=adult&amp;locked=false&amp;pagination_page=1&amp;query=mahalia+jackson&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=keyword&amp;sort=relevancy" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Mahalia Jackson</a>. Let's meet a few of the others.</p>
<p>In 1931, singer and choir director Magnolia Lewis Butts worked alongside pianist Thomas A. Dorsey to establish the city's first gospel choir at <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-ebenezer-missionary-baptist-church-archives/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Ebenezer Baptist Church</a>. She simultaneously adopted gospel music for the youth choir she directed at <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-coalition-to-save-the-met-archives/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Metropolitan Community Church</a>. Just a year later, Butts and singer Sallie Martin were among the small group of notables who established the <a href="http://ncgccinc.com/wp/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">National Convention of Gospel Choirs and Choruses</a> in Chicago. Their first convention was held at Pilgrim Baptist Church in 1933. <a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/entertainment/museums/ct-ent-national-gospel-museum-chicago-plans-revealed-1208-story.html" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">A National Museum of Gospel Music has been proposed for this site.</a></p>
<p>By 1933, Chicago's radio waves also had a woman's touch when the "Glorious Church of the Air" broadcast the gospel program of All Nations Pentecostal Church. Elder Lucy Smith, who founded her church in 1918, was the first black woman to pastor to a major congregation in Chicago. Her granddaughter, <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-lucy-smith-collier-papers-2/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Lucy Smith Collier</a>, first rose to fame with the Lucy Smith Singers and later served as the pianist for Chicago's Roberta Martin Singers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-martin-and-morris-music-company-papers/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Sallie Martin</a>, also noted above, formed the Colored Ladies Quartet, America's first all-female gospel singing group (renamed the Sallie Martin Singers), which featured a young Dinah Washington, then known as Ruth Jones. Martin also recognized gospel's importance as a business. In 1940, she and her husband began the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/martin-morris-gospel-sheet-music-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Martin and Morris Music Company</a> to manage music publishing. Around 1,500 scores are in CPL's collection. </p>
<p>The gospel sounds of Lucy Smith Collier, along with Felicia Coleman-Evans, Rev. Myrtle Jackson, Loretta Oliver, Mavis Staples, Albertina Walker and several local church choirs can be heard on <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/jubilee-showcase-gospel-music-video-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Jubilee Showcase recordings</a> or from appearances with the legendary <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-rev-clay-evans-archive/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Fellowship Missionary Baptist Church</a> choir, led for three decades by Lou Della Evans-Reid. Gospel historian Bob Marovich interviewed Evans-Reid for this <a href="http://journalofgospelmusic.com/conversations-gospel-legends/conversations-gospel-legends-dr-lou-della-evans-reid/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Conversations with Gospel Legends</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/events/5a297c416aa8242500d542fd" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Lou Della Evans-Reid's Traditional Choir performs Saturday, March 3 at Harold Washington Library Center.</a> This event celebrates both <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/news/celebrate-womens-history-month-with-cpl-4/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Women's History Month</a> and this year's <a href="http://www.onebookonechicago.org/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">One Book, One Chicago</a> season exploring the theme "Music: The Beat of Our City" through Greg Kot's book <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1899074126">I'll Take You There</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remembering Chicagoan Lerone Bennett, Jr.</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/remembering-lerone-bennett-jr/</link>
		<comments>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/remembering-lerone-bennett-jr/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 22:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cynthia]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African American history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=175590</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chicagoan and African American historian and editor Lerone Bennett, Jr. died Wednesday, February 14 at 89. Bennett began a long and storied publishing career first writing for the Atlanta Daily World, while also serving as city editor for Jet magazine. In 1953, he became the associate editor of Ebony. Five years later, he accepted the…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chicagoan and African American historian and editor Lerone Bennett, Jr. died Wednesday, February 14 at 89.</p>
<p>Bennett began a long and storied publishing career first writing for the <em>Atlanta Daily World</em>, while also serving as city editor for <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=5joDAAAAMBAJ&amp;source=gbs_all_issues_r&amp;cad=1&amp;atm_aiy=1950#all_issues_anchor" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Jet magazine</a>. In 1953, he became the associate editor of <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=PtMDAAAAMBAJ&amp;source=gbs_all_issues_r&amp;cad=1&amp;atm_aiy=1950#all_issues_anchor" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Ebony</a>. Five years later, he accepted the position of executive editor.</p>
<p>In addition to his journalistic endeavors, Bennett was also an author. Perhaps most popular is his 1962 work, <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1187580126">Before the Mayflower</a>, a history of black America beginning in 1619. At least eight editions of the title were published, including a 25<sup>th</sup> anniversary edition and a reprint of the 1962 edition. He also wrote <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/785309126">What Manner of Man,</a> a Martin Luther King, Jr. biography. In 2000, Bennett published the controversial <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/754795126">Forced Into Glory: Abraham Lincoln’s White Dream</a>, a book that echoed a 1968 Ebony article in which Bennett asked if Lincoln was a white supremacist.</p>

<p>Bennett was a tireless advocate for civil rights and the end to Jim Crow practices in the South. An account of a trip to the South in the mid-1950s with white Ebony photographer Mike Shea can be found in the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/vivian-g-harsh-research-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Vivian G. Harsh Research Collection</a>’s <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-ben-burns-papers/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Ben Burns Papers</a>. There, Bennett relates how he was inevitably questioned by police; how he had to travel in a separate rental car; as well as dine and sleep separately: “[A]s expected, [M]ike could always find a good hotel, while [I] had to settle for dumps and greasy eating places. [W]here to meet was always a problem.”</p>
<p>An icon of the black studies movement, Bennett was a frequent speaker at Olive-Harvey College’s annual Black Studies Conference. He served on the board of Chicago Public Library while Harold Washington was mayor. And <a href="http://gatekeeper.chipublib.org/login?url=https://search.proquest.com/docview/1019016716?accountid=303" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">he wrote a musical about the late mayor, entitled “Harold’s Journey,”</a> which was performed at Orchestra Hall in 1989.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in black journalism in Chicago, explore the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-ben-burns-papers/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Ben Burns Papers</a>, the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-abbott-sengstacke-family-papers-2/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Abbott-Sengstacke Family Papers</a> or the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-mcgill-family-papers-2/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">McGill Family Papers</a>. We also have the papers of a few of Bennett’s contemporaries, such as <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-timuel-d-black-papers/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Timuel Black, Jr.</a> and <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-leonard-wash-papers/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Leonard Wash</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/remembering-lerone-bennett-jr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Philip Sang Collection Documents African American Experience</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/philip-sang-collection-documents-african-american-experience/</link>
		<comments>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/philip-sang-collection-documents-african-american-experience/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cynthia]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African American history]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=174434</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chicago Public Library recently digitized over 200 items documenting the African American experience. You can see these items in our Philip David Sang Digital Collection. The Sang collection, acquired by CPL in the late 1970s and housed in the Vivian G. Harsh Research Collection at Woodson Regional Library, consists of a range of materials and…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chicago Public Library recently digitized over 200 items documenting the African American experience. You can see these items in our <a href="https://cdm16818.contentdm.oclc.org/customizations/global/pages/content.php?id=p16818coll6" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Philip David Sang Digital Collection</a>.</p>
<p>The Sang collection, acquired by CPL in the late 1970s and housed in the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/vivian-g-harsh-research-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Vivian G. Harsh Research Collection</a> at <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/locations/81/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Woodson Regional Library</a>, consists of a range of materials and subjects. Among the oldest items in the collection is a <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/id/697/rec/1" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">mid-18<sup>th</sup> century map of western Africa</a>.</p>
<p>Most of the digitized items pertain to slavery in the United States. Materials derived from the <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/search/searchterm/bill%20of%20sale/field/all/mode/all/conn/and/order/nosort/ad/asc" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">domestic slave trade</a> cast a long shadow over our shared history. However, there’s an obvious theme of resistance that shines through the stories represented in <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/search/searchterm/fugitive%20slave/field/all/mode/all/conn/and/order/nosort/ad/asc" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">runaway slave advertisements</a>. There are also documents and published works created during the abolition and Civil War eras, as well as several items from the 20<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>Some of the more noteworthy items in the collection are a <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/id/295/rec/3" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">"Negro Passport,"</a> which was a document issued during the Civil War by the Confederate Army and carried by enslaved men forced into providing military services for slave owners. There’s also a <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/id/416/rec/1" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Certificate of Freedom issued in 1814</a>; a <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/search/searchterm/frederick%20douglass%20correspondence" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">trio of letters from Frederick Douglass</a> and a <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/id/508/rec/1" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">signature book from an 1886 reunion of abolitionists</a>.</p>
<p>Controversially, the collection contains a <a href="http://digital.chipublib.org/digital/collection/p16818coll6/id/768/rec/1" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">1906 children’s book</a>, published here in Chicago, in which African Americans are portrayed as stereotypical caricatures. The book’s not-so-subtle racism serves as testament to the uphill battles faced by African Americans long after the Civil War ended.</p>
<p>To learn more, check out the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-philip-david-sang-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Philip David Sang Collection finding aid</a>. Materials that are not available digitally, such as an autographed copy of <a href="http://content.time.com/time/covers/0,16641,19640103,00.html" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.’s 1964 Time magazine cover</a>, will be made available electronically in person at the Harsh Collection.</p>
<p>We’re pleased to bring this collection to life and make it accessible to everyone online. You can see additional materials from CPL's special collections in our <a href="https://cdm16818.contentdm.oclc.org/customizations/global/pages/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Digital Collections</a> or by visiting us in person.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/philip-sang-collection-documents-african-american-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remembering Chicago Actor John Mahoney</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/remembering-john-mahoney/</link>
		<comments>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/remembering-john-mahoney/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 21:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=174714</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[John Mahoney, the Tony Award-winning Chicago actor and Steppenwolf Theatre Company ensemble member, died Sunday. Like so many others, I remember Mahoney fondly in the role of Martin Crane on Frasier. He became a welcome family member in my living room, helping me study and laugh through library school. It wasn’t until I came to…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?frbr=false&amp;locked=false&amp;query=John+Mahoney&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">John Mahoney</a>, the Tony Award-winning Chicago actor and Steppenwolf Theatre Company ensemble member, died Sunday.</p>
<p>Like so many others, I remember Mahoney fondly in the role of Martin Crane on <em>Frasier</em>. He became a welcome family member in my living room, helping me study and laugh through library school. It wasn’t until I came to Chicago and began working with the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_subject/theater/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Chicago Theater Collection,</a> that I learned what a mark he had made locally.</p>
<p>Mahoney was nearly 40 when he began acting professionally. He had been working as an associate editor for the <em>Quality Review Bulletin of the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals</em> to pay the bills. On the side, he took acting classes at the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_post/st-nicholas-theatre-company-archives/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">St. Nicholas Theatre Company,</a> where he played a part in the 1977 world premiere of <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?custom_edit=false&amp;query=%28title%3A%28The+Water+Engine%29+AND+contributor%3A%28David+Mamet%29+%29&amp;searchType=bl&amp;suppress=true" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">The Water Engine</a> by <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=Mamet%2C+David&amp;searchType=author" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">David Mamet</a>.</p>
<p>Mahoney graced many stages throughout his career, playing regularly at Northlight Theatre in Skokie, as well as National Jewish Theatre and Irish Repertory in Chicago. However, he was best known for his stage work at <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_post/steppenwolf-theatre-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Steppenwolf Theatre,</a> where he joined the ensemble in 1979. Mahoney acted in over three dozen productions at the theater over nearly 40 years. Take a look back at some of his early roles in the photos in this post, as documented by then-Steppenwolf photographer <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_post/lisa-ebright-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Lisa Howe-Ebright</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/remembering-john-mahoney/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going for Gold: Chicago&#8217;s History with Winter Sports</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/going-for-gold-chicagos-history-with-winter-sports/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 14:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Johanna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago Park District]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Olympics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=174256</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 2018 Winter Olympics begin February 9 in PyeongChang, South Korea. Looking to get into the Olympic spirit? Check out our recommendations for remembering 1980's Miracle on Ice, exploring different sports and events with the kids in your life, memoirs of famous athletes and winter sports movies. But maybe you want even more? Well, look…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.olympic.org/pyeongchang-2018" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">2018 Winter Olympics</a> begin February 9 in PyeongChang, South Korea. Looking to get into the Olympic spirit? Check out our recommendations for <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/miracle-on-ice-35th-anniversary/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">remembering 1980's Miracle on Ice</a>, <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/when-i-grow-up-i-want-to-go-to-the-olympics/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">exploring different sports and events with the kids in your life</a>, <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/olympic-sized-moments/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">memoirs of famous athletes</a> and <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?frbr=false&amp;locked=false&amp;pagination_page=1&amp;query=%28subject%3A%28skating%29+OR+subject%3A%28hockey%29+OR+subject%3A%28skiing%29+OR+subject%3A%28bobsledding%29+OR+subject%3A%28Olympic+Winter+Games.%29+%29+formatcode%3A%28DVD+OR+VIDEO_ONLINE+%29&amp;searchScope=IL-CPL&amp;searchType=bl&amp;sort=relevancy" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">winter sports movies</a>.</p>
<p>But maybe you want even more? Well, look no further than Chicago's past to get more Olympic vibes. Chicago has hosted several international sporting competitions, from the Pan American Games in 1959 to the Special Olympics beginning in 1968 to the Gay Games in 2006. And while spectating is the closest most of us will get to a real gold medal, that hasn't stopped amateur athletes here in Chicago from embracing our wintery climate throughout the city's history to enjoy a variety of winter sports.</p>
<p>You can visit <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/special-collections/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Special Collections</a> at <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/locations/34/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Harold Washington Library Center</a> to read how Chicago's park administrators encouraged Chicagoans to get active in winter. The 1917 publication <a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1819317126" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Playgrounds and Recreation Centers of the West Chicago Park Commissioners</a> explains how in each park, "the play field is flooded in the winter time, in order that people may enjoy the invigorating sport of ice skating."</p>
<p>You can also view a brochure in our <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-chicago-city-wide-collection-2/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Chicago City-Wide Collection</a> that promotes a state-of-the-art indoor ice skating rink at Broadway and Thorndale that was ultimately turned into a National Guard Armory.</p>
<p>Find out what kind of ice skates you could have bought in the 1920s from Chicago-based Nestor Johnson Manufacturing Company in our <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/fa-trade-catalog-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Trade Catalog Collection</a>. The catalogs also list results of speed skating competitions.</p>
<p>And visit our <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_subject/neighborhoods/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Neighborhood History Research Collection</a> and our <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/archival_subject/parks/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Chicago Park District Collections</a> to see photographs of people enjoying such winter sports as cross-country skiing, ice skating and speed skating, ski jumping (yes, really!), sledding and dog sledding, ice boat racing, sledge hockey and more.</p>
<p>What's your favorite winter sport?</p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quiz: Do You Know Chicago&#8217;s Music Landmarks?</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/quiz-chicago-music-landmarks/</link>
		<comments>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/quiz-chicago-music-landmarks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 15:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Book One Chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OBOC 2017-2018]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quizzes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=174100</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This season of One Book, One Chicago, we're celebrating the theme of Music: The Beat of Our City through Greg Kot's book I'll Take You There. As we explore Chicago's rich musical heritage, we want to know, how well do you know Chicago Landmarks? Take our quiz, written by librarian Mary from the Municipal Reference Collection…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.chipublib.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2018/01/Chicago-Theater.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-174118" src="https://www.chipublib.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2018/01/Chicago-Theater-300x230.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="230"></a>This season of <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/browse_program/one-book-one-chicago/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">One Book, One Chicago</a>, we're celebrating the theme of Music: The Beat of Our City through Greg Kot's book <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1899074126">I'll Take You There</a>. As we explore Chicago's rich musical heritage, we want to know, how well do you know <a href="http://webapps.cityofchicago.org/landmarksweb/web/home.htm" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Chicago Landmarks</a>? Take our quiz, written by librarian Mary from the <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/welcome-to-the-municipal-reference-collection/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Municipal Reference Collection</a> at <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/locations/34/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Harold Washington Library Center</a>, and find out!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/quiz-chicago-music-landmarks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Books to Celebrate the Illinois Bicentennial</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/books-to-celebrate-illinoiss-bicentennial/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SarahD]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illinois history]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=173560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Illinois became a state nearly 200 years ago, on December 3, 1818. The state's celebrating the Illinois Bicentennial all year long with events throughout Illinois. Here at CPL, we'll celebrate by recommending resources on our state's history and culture each month. To get us started, here are some suggestions for learning more about the history…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Illinois became a state nearly 200 years ago, on December 3, 1818. The state's celebrating the <a href="https://illinois200.com/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Illinois Bicentennial</a> all year long with <a href="https://illinois200.com/celebrate/events/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">events throughout Illinois</a>. Here at CPL, we'll celebrate by recommending resources on our state's history and culture each month. To get us started, here are some suggestions for learning more about the history of Illinois.</p>
<p>For a good overview, <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/728333126">Illinois: Crossroads of a Continent</a> provides a look at the history of the state from Native Americans to the 1990s, touching on many topics. The book includes a smattering of black-and-white photos.</p>
<p>Regarding Illinois' early history, did you know the <a href="https://cahokiamounds.org/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Cahokia mounds</a> near present-day Collinsville are considered the largest and most important prehistoric archaeological structures north of Mexico? You can visit this state historic site, or you can read about it, and the Mississippian people who lived there, in <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/869297126">Cahokia: Mirror of the Cosmos</a>.</p>
<p>Shortly after Illinois became a state and was still the "Far West" of the country, Christiana Holmes Tillson and her husband moved from Massachusetts to Illinois. The journey was long and at times treacherous. Tillson shares her experience in <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/567385126">A Woman's Story of Pioneer Illinois</a>. Skim through the numerous mentions of people she met or knew to get to the more interesting bits. For example, there was already a fair amount of animosity and prejudice between Northerners and Southerners, as made clear by the interactions she had with the many Southerners who had settled in Illinois. Slavery in Illinois was legal under certain conditions (not to be outlawed until 1848, and even then it continued somewhat until the Civil War), and the Tillsons acquired two slaves, although she says she felt conflicted about it.</p>
<p>One thing Illinois is well-known for today is, unfortunately, its corruption. <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1654416126">Corrupt Illinois</a> covers crooked politicians from governors to aldermen to treasurers and beyond, and discusses the culture of bribery, nepotism and machine politics that still endures here. In Chicago, "Bathhouse" John Coughlin, "Hinky Dink" Kenna and Johnny "Da Pow" Powers were part of the Council of the Gray Wolves, which lasted from the 1890s to the 1930s. More recently, between 1973 and 2013, 33 Chicago aldermen and former aldermen have been convicted of federal crimes relating to their service.</p>
<p>To end with something a little more lighthearted, <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1484268126">Weird Illinois</a> takes a look at the strange and the spooky in our state. From the Murphysboro Mud Monster to the world's largest catsup bottle, Illinois has plenty of oddities and legends to offer.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Outdoors: Illinois Conservation Magazine</title>
		<link>https://www.chipublib.org/blogs/post/the-great-outdoors-in-illinois-conservation-magazine/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 20:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SarahD]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illinois history]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chipublib.org/?p=168644</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many state agencies and departments publish, or published, their own newsletters, bulletins and other periodicals. These can be fun to browse because they include information and pictures that aren’t often available elsewhere.  The Illinois Department of Conservation’s Illinois Conservation magazine focused on hunting, fishing and the great outdoors. The early issues in particular were more…]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many state agencies and departments publish, or published, their own newsletters, bulletins and other periodicals. These can be fun to browse because they include information and pictures that aren’t often available elsewhere. </p>
<p>The Illinois Department of Conservation’s <a class="o-link--solid-faux-underline add_title_widget" href="http://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/item/show/1636710126">Illinois Conservation</a> magazine focused on hunting, fishing and the great outdoors.</p>
<p>The early issues in particular were more chatty and less formal than departmental publications are today. For example, the Spring 1937 issue featured an “Autobiography of a Ring-Necked Pheasant” by William H. Long. The story, as “revealed” to the author, includes a cautionary tale for farmers about the dangers of mowing machines.</p>
<p>It's also interesting to see how attitudes change over time.  For example, a story such as "Pity the Hunter's Wife--for hers is the job of preparing his game for the table," from the Fall 1938 issue, would probably not appear in a government magazine today.</p>
<p>Current events affected the magazine, too. The December 1942 issue was subtitled the “Win the War” issue and described how the department was aiding the war effort. Throughout World War II, readers were frequently urged to buy war bonds and stamps. The Department of Conservation also helped arrange recreation programs such as fishing trips for veterans recuperating from illnesses and injuries at the Great Lakes Naval Hospital.</p>
<p>To take a closer look at these issues and others, visit the Government Publications Department on the 5th floor of <a href="https://www.chipublib.org/locations/34/" class="o-link--solid-faux-underline">Harold Washington Library Center</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
